in Jesus name amen and amen
uh first I want to wish happy Sabbath to
everyone uh
welcome to uh living Mana online church
for those of you who may be joining for
the first time
uh we're glad to have you here
for those of you who attend regularly
um welcome it is good to have you here
good to see you in the chat
and um we are going to be dealing with a
controversial issue uh today uh it is
evangelism Sabbath and so
on evangelism sabbaths what we do we
actually creating a playlist of all the
evangelism sabbaths we've done so far
they happen once a month and we deal
with doctrinal issues
the Sabbath The Law of God what happens
to a person when they die Etc
um yep that's right thank you for me uh
we're about to get Instagram on here
live you all saw that
uh okay
so I think we are good to go Instagram
just let me
um
make sure that y'all are y'all are good
okay excellent there we go there we go
okay
so um
we are going to be dealing with a
subject that is controversial and it
deals with the identity of the children
of Israel
um I want to forewarn you uh even though
you should not need it because you know
when you come to living manna
you're not going to get something other
than living Mana right you're gonna get
word and a lot of it
so
we want to we want to answer the
question
um
who
are
the Israelites who are the children of
Israel that's the big question we're
going to go to our screen
and um as you'll see the title of this
message is the controversy over the
identity of the children of Israel and
uh we're gonna start here
you all know that uh Kyrie Irving was in
the news recently
and
um it brought to a greater stage if you
will uh the Black Hebrew Israelite
movement or simply put the Hebrew
Israelite movement
um many see it as an extremist uh sect
and others believe that this is this is
the true Remnant spoken about in Bible
prophecy
that
um there are evidences in the scriptures
that point to
um
black people being the true
uh Israel of God
and um I want to talk about some of the
things that their different sects within
uh the Hebrew Israelite movement
but here's some of the things they
believe they believe that the true
Israelites are black Hispanic Etc they
keep all the Commandments and statutes
meaning not just the Ten Commandments
but all 623
um Commandments that can be found in the
Old Testament give or take
um many of these uh uh factions believe
that white people uh will not or cannot
and that should be
white people won't or can't I put will
or can't by accident but black white
people I'm sorry I read that wrong no
white people will or can be saved but
will be enslaved
um
during the New Kingdom uh will be
enslaved to black people in the New
Kingdom
so that's one of the beliefs of uh
certain segments of Hebrew Israelites
now if you're a Hebrew Israelite and
you're watching right now
um you know I don't believe that I get
that you know you could I'm not making a
blanket statement here
um but I am pointing out specific
beliefs beliefs
of the movement that are held by at
least a significant amount of people in
that movement okay uh they also believe
that the 400 years of captivity is a
prophetic fulfillment
um that identifies uh African Americans
as the true Israelites so the 400 years
of captivity uh the transatlantic slave
trade is a fulfillment of Bible prophecy
we're going to be looking at that
they believe that all the prophecies and
promises are centered on Israel
according to Bloodline
and they believe that God favors a
certain group of people based on
bloodline so again uh you might find
different people who say no we you know
our camp or our sect doesn't believe
this this this but we believe this this
this so again this is generally speaking
okay now
there is another segment to this because
you have the the white Evangelical
support of Israel meaning the the the
people who are in the land of Israel
right now
um
they believe that all prophecy
all prophecy is centered on Israel so
they speak about such things as the
temple an antichrist all focusing or
centering on what's happening in
Jerusalem they believe that God favors a
certain group of people based on
Bloodlines so God's favorite people are
the Jews and then the Gentiles kind of
get to tag along so very similar right
except you know one group by and large
believes that Gentiles can be saved but
they're not they're not the favored
people of God whereas the other group no
Gentiles at least
a certain type of Gentiles cannot be
saved at all
um by the way the the Hebrew Israelite
movement believes that in certain cases
when the Bible speaks about Gentiles and
the Gentiles being saved that it's
really talking about
uh other uh Israelites other Israelites
okay
so um here are the two different groups
there's white Evangelical Christianity
and there is the Hebrew Israelite
movement and you know again we see the
Hebrew Israelite movement getting some
some a lot of notice today uh
today because of
you know a lot of things happening in in
society and they're becoming
um they're getting more attention and a
lot of young black men are joining
this movement
so again
uh with Black History Month going on
right now it's like I said it's kind of
hard to
address different topics and not deal
with this one okay so are y'all ready to
get down you all ready to study put a
one in the chat if you're ready to study
that was just the introduction
we're gonna we're gonna we're gonna
start getting into the word of God and
and what I want to do is basically set
the foundation uh for what we're going
to study today okay
um so we're gonna go to Genesis chapter
12 and the first thing I want to do is
basically talk about the history of
Israel that's what we're going to talk
about the history of Israel
so the history of to understand the
history of Israel we have to actually go
back to Abraham
and I'm going to lay out some things
here and I just want you to follow along
because we're building up to something
here but notice with me Genesis chapter
12 verse 2 and 3. the Bible says here
speaking God speaking of Abraham I will
make of thee a great nation and I will
bless thee and make thy name great and
thou shall be a blessing
and I will bless them that bless thee
and curse him that cursed thee and in
these shall all the nations of the earth
be blessed okay
so the first thing that I want you to
recognize that you may not have
understood before or put together before
is this
this call of Abraham right that God is
gonna bless uh make a bless all the
families of the earth through him
is
a symbol of the very work of Christ
it's a symbol of the very work of Christ
so do me a favor put a one in the chat
if you understand what I mean when I say
it is a symbol of the very work of
Christ
um just as the Bible promised that all
nations would be blessed in Abraham
so when Christ came to this world it was
for the purpose of these nations whoever
they are to be blessed in him through
him as the Messiah in fact
in Galatians 3 14 the Bible actually
spells it out for us the Bible says that
the blessing of Abraham
might come on the Gentiles
through
who
Jesus Christ
that we might receive the promise of the
spirit through faith so the only
connection that I'm making right now is
I want you to understand that Abraham
was a type of Christ
he was a type of Christ meaning just as
people were going to be blessed by being
connected to Abraham or coming through
Abraham
so people are blessed who are connected
with Christ or through Christ
does that make sense so far let's put a
one in the chat
if that makes sense put a one in the
chat if that makes sense Abraham was a
foreshadow of Jesus in that Justice
all who are in Abraham are blessed
so all who are in Jesus are blessed and
we know obviously that Jesus is greater
than Abraham right so Abraham is
pointing to one greater than himself
which is Jesus okay
but the story doesn't stop at Abraham
Abraham had a son by the way let's look
at Galatians 3 29 just to amplify that
point if you be Christ then are ye
Abraham's seed and heirs according to
the promise now this is not answering
the question of who if who be christs
right we're not dealing with that
question yet we're simply saying that
those who belong to Christ or who are in
Christ
parallels those who are in Abraham
does that make sense so as the promise
to Abraham is those who are in Abraham
those who are in Abraham will be blessed
to a greater degree those who are in
Christ
will be blessed so Abraham is like a a
object lesson of Christ
all right
okay so far so good
Abraham has a son that son's name is
Isaac
and I want you to notice we're going to
see something very similar when it comes
to Isaac in Genesis 22 verse 2 the Bible
said it's God's speaking here
to Abraham take not thy son
thine only son Isaac
and get thee into the land of Moriah and
offer him therefore burnt offering upon
one of the mountains which I shall tell
thee of so do you all see what's
happening here
not only
is Abraham a type of Christ
in that just as those who are in Abraham
are blessed so those who are in Christ
are blessed but now we see that Isaac
the son of Abraham is offered up as a
sacrifice
now we know that that sacrifice has
stopped short but the point is Isaac is
also a type of Christ
right for God so loved the world that he
gave his only begotten son that
whosoever believeth in him should not
perish but have everlasting life so just
as Isaac was given up as a sacrifice but
of course that sacrifice didn't happen
he was it was pointing to Jesus who
would be the ultimate sacrifice
so all I want you to see right now
is that Abraham points to Christ
Isaac
points to Christ and so what do you
think I'm about to show you next
what do you think I'm about to show you
next
we're about to talk about Jacob
I want you to notice Genesis 32 verse
28.
and he said thy name shall be called No
More Jacob but Israel for as a prince
thou has power with God and with men and
has prevailed
so we know that Isaac's son is Jacob
Jacob and Esau but Jacob is the pro is
the promised one Jacob is the one
through who the lineage is gonna go and
I want you to note that it is Jacob
whose name is changed
to Israel
all right so y'all see that Abraham
points to Christ Isaac points to Christ
and now we're at Jacob and the obvious
question we're going to look at is does
Jacob point to Christ
remember Jacob is a man who wrestles
with God he wrestles with God and
overcomes and his name is changed let me
see if I can break it down for you this
way
Jacob starts out or let me say Israel
starts out as a man
who then
multiplies to 12 men
and then multiplies to a great multitude
so what do you mean Pastor
so remember first we had Israel
first we had Israel you can't have the
children of Israel without Israel so you
got Israel who was formerly Jacob
Israel has 12 sons Genesis 35 22 not the
sons of Jacob were 12. so Israel has 12
sons and these sons are the sons of
Israel the children
of Israel
so I want you to think about it what's
your father's name just think about your
father's name and if you have siblings
you all will be like well we're the
children of Ronnie that's my father or
we're the children of whatever your
father's name is that's what that that's
what it's saying here
these are the children of Israel they
started out as 12. but we know that
eventually
the Bible says in Exodus 1 verse 7 and
the children of Israel were fruitful and
increased abundantly and multiplied and
waxed exceeding Mighty and the land was
filled with them the land was filled
with them so here's what we see Israel
starts out as a man
multiplies into 12
and then multiplies into a great
multitude put a one in the chat if you
all are following what I'm saying
he multiplies into it he turns into he
goes from a man an individual one person
to 12
offspring
to a great multitude
okay
so far so good
um I also want you to notice something
about Israel in Exodus chapter 4 verse
22 the Bible says and thou shall say
unto Pharaoh thus say the Lord Israel is
my son even my firstborn now I want you
to pause for a second because that's a
very interesting way to put that there
Israel is my son singular not the
Israelites are my children
but Israel is my son
even my firstborn that's a weird
statement y'all put a five in the chat
if you're like yeah that's worded
kind of weird because we know that
Israel at this time is a great multitude
a great nation so why is God calling
Israel
his son
as if Israel is an individual
a person a single person why would God
do something like that verse 23 and I
say unto thee let my son go that he may
serve me and if you refuse to let him go
behold I will slay thy son even thy
first born
okay so here we have Israel who is
called God's firstborn or his son
now
let's begin to break this down y'all
because what I want you to see
what I want you to see
is that it is after this that Jesus goes
into I'm sorry I'm jumping ahead of
myself it is after this that Israel upon
escaping out of Egypt they go they cross
the Red Sea and they go into the
Wilderness they go into the wilderness
now let's pause right here and I want to
go back to something
you do realize that just as Jacob
wrestled alone with God
so Jesus in The Garden of Gethsemane
also wrestled with God put a one in the
chat if you understand what I just said
Matthew 26 36 then cometh Jesus with
them unto a place called Gethsemane and
safe unto the unto his disciples sit you
here while I go and pray Yonder remember
what what what
Jacob did when he told everybody hey
he left he sent his family ahead and he
alone stayed behind
and he ends up wrestling with this
Divine being
you know what's happening here in the
garden
jesus takes some of his disciples but he
says stay here I have to go do this
myself
and he took with him Peter and the two
sons of Zebedee and began to be
sorrowful and very heavy so let me keep
reading then he saved unto them my soul
is exceeding sorrowful even unto death
tarry here and watch with me and he went
a little further and fell on his face
and prayed
same for my father if it be possible let
this cup pass from me nevertheless not
as I will but as thy will so what do we
have happening here just as
Jacob
wrestled with God so we find Jesus alone
in the garden wrestling with God now you
say well Pastor that's coincidence well
let's keep going
remember how I said to you that Jacob
started as a man
but then multiplied into 12.
notice with me Matthew chapter 10 verse
1 and when he had called unto him his
he's what
his 12 disciples he gave them power
against unclean spirits to cast them out
and to heal all manner of sickness and
all manner of diseases so watch this
jacob starts up at Israel starts out as
one man
who multiplies by 12 or is Multiplied he
has 12 sons
Jesus
we're going to see in a moment but just
check this out Jesus
is one man
who multiplies who who produces 12
disciples so let's keep going
in Acts chapter 2 verse 41 the Bible
says then they that were that gladly
received his word were baptized and the
same there day they were added unto them
about 3 000 Souls now very interesting
because Jacob starts as one man Israel
starts as one man multiplies into 12 in
other words he's got 12 Offspring and
from that 12
from that 12 they produce a great
multitude very interesting that Jesus is
a man who multiplies by 12 the 12
disciples and from that 12.
from that 12.
you have 3 000 who are baptized who will
ultimately grow into a great great great
great multitude
I want you to know this
in Matthew 2 verse 13 the Bible says and
when they departed behold the angel of
the Lord appeared to Joseph in a dream
saying arise and take the young child
that is Jesus and his mother and flee
into Egypt and be thou there until I
bring the word for Herod will seek the
young child to destroy him when he arose
he took the young child and his mother
by night and departed into Egypt watch
this
and was there until the death of Herod
that it might be fulfilled which was the
which was spoken of the Lord by the
prophet saying out of Egypt have I
called my son whoa
wait a minute
out of Egypt have I called my son what
is God talking about that happened way
back there in The Exodus and now we see
oh Israel the man Israel
was a type of Jesus himself so then
Not only was Abraham a type of Christ
Not only was Isaac a type of Christ but
Jacob whose name is changed to Israel
who starts as well as one man multiplies
by 12 and then grows into a great
multitude
is also a type of Christ who went
through the exact experience down to the
place where God here is literally
calling Jesus Israel by name
Israel
Jesus's name
is also symbolically Israel
out of each have I called my son what
son Israel go back and read it in Exodus
chapter 3.
Exodus chapter 2.
okay so please know this
just as the children of Israel crossed
the Red Sea remember that they crossed
the Red Sea which is a symbol of baptism
notice that Jesus the second Israel so
watch this Jesus was the second Abraham
Jesus was the second Isaac Jesus is the
second was the second Israel and note
this then cometh Jesus From Galilee to
Jordan unto John to be baptized of him
but John forbade him saying I have need
to be baptized of thee and comes out to
me Jesus answered and said unto them
suffered to be so so for now for those
who becometh us to fulfill our
righteousness then he suffered him and
Jesus when he was baptized went up
straightway out of the water and lo the
heavens were open unto him and he saw
the spirit of God descending upon him
and lighting upon him so remember Israel
leaves Egypt crosses the Red Sea as a
symbol of baptism and then where do they
go they go into the Wilderness for how
long
come on somebody for how long
how long is Jesus in the wilderness
he is in the wilderness for for and
for 40 days how long did Israel spend in
the wilderness after they crossed the
Red Sea which was a symbol of baptism 40
years the Bible says in Matthew 4 1 then
was Jesus led up into this let up of the
spirit Into the Wilderness to be tempted
of the devil and when he had fasted 40
days and 40 nights he was afterward 100.
so here you have an amazing parallel an
amazing parallel that shows that in
actuality Israel has its fulfillment in
Christ
so now our question is this if you are
with me so far just give me an amen put
a one in the chat there should be no one
right now who's against what I'm saying
because I haven't mentioned who is you
know who are the true we're not talking
about any of that yet I'm just laying
out of foundation
all right y'all with me so far Okay so
the question we need to ask now is who
is this great nation that will Spring
forth from
Jesus
are y'all with me
Jacob one man name is changed to Israel
one man who becomes twelve who becomes a
great multitude
in the New Testament we have Jesus who
is literally as it were the Fulfillment
of everything Jacob did
he is the Israel who starts as one man
multiplies by 12.
produces a great multitude comes out of
Egypt goes acrosses the the a river
symbolizing baptism and is in the
wilderness for 40 days and 40 nights
he's imp he's the embodiment of both the
person is real and the nation is real
he's the embodiment of both the
individual and the nation
so the question then is who is
the nation that Jesus came to save
we got two options it's either everybody
or it's just the Israelites
right that those are the options before
us
so in order to find out this question we
have to go back even further than
Abraham
and so what we're going to do is we're
going to go back to the very beginning
that's where we need to go are y'all
with me is that fair we can't just start
in the middle of the Old Testament we
can't we can't start in the New
Testament we got to go a bit if you want
to get the full context we got to go way
back to the beginning so let's go way
back to the beginning but to go way back
to the beginning I need to go to Luke
chapter 3 verse 38 don't laugh we're
actually going to the beginning
but we're gonna find the beginning in
Luke chapter 3 verse 38. so let's go
there Luke chapter 3 verse 38 here is
the genealogy a genial genealogical list
being given
um in Luke chapter three speaking about
the genealogy of Christ
and the genealogy is working backwards
right so starting from Jesus and then it
goes back back and it's going all the
way back to Adam so I want you to know
this verse 38 says which was the son of
Venus which was the son of Seth which
was the son of Adam and that's going to
tell us who Adam is
Adam which was the son of God now that's
interesting
Adam
the son of God
well we know that title really only you
know I mean when you hear the Son of God
who do you think about you think about
Jesus right but here Adam is being
called the Son of God not only is Adam
called the Son of God but watch this in
Genesis 1 26 God said let us make man in
our image and after our likeness so in
other words this son of God was made in
the image of God put a one in the chat
if y'all are following me
this son of God was made in the image of
God now I need you to keep that in mind
because again we're setting Foundation
here line upon line precept upon precept
this son of God was made in the image of
God but I want you to know what happens
in Genesis 2 17 they are warned if you
eat from the Tree of the knowledge of
Good and Evil you will surely what
you're surely
going to die
you're surely going to die and what
happens is Adam and Eve eat from the
tree when the woman saw that the tree
was good for food and that it was
pleasant to the eyes and a tree to be
desired to make one wise she took of the
fruit and did eat and gave also unto her
husband with her and he did eat and the
eyes of them both were open
so
please note what's going on here
this atom or the first son of God
disobeys God and the sentence of death
is pronounced upon him
now why is it significant because what I
want you to note is in First Corinthians
chapter 15 verse 45 the Bible says add
and so it is written the first man Adam
was made a living soul and the last atom
was made of quickening spirit so watch
this y'all the last Adam we're speaking
about here is Jesus
So Not only was Abraham a type of Christ
Not only was Isaac a type of Christ Not
only was was uh Jacob meaning Israel a
type of Christ we also see that Adam
himself was a type of Christ the son of
God made in the image of God
a type of Christ
why is that significant to understand
for the question at hand
well yeah I'm watching the water I'm
watching the water
notice Romans chapter 5 verse 12. the
Bible says wherefore as by one man
sin entered into the world now pause for
a second who is the one man by which sin
entered into the world
who's the one man by which sin enter
into the world put it in the chat
Instagram put it in the chat YouTube
Facebook who was the one man by which
sin entered the world
it's Adam
right so watch this and so death passed
upon all men for that all have sinned so
here's my question very pointed question
now
who is affected by this one man's sin
is it
is it a certain group of people is it
some people or is it everybody
what do y'all think
all right I'm seeing all in the chat
Instagram y'all say all too so just if
anyone disagrees uh that it wasn't
everybody that's affected it's not the
whole earth it's only a certain group of
people that then put that in the chat
who are the group of people that Adam
sinning affected
if it's not everybody then it's a
certain group who is that group of
people
now I don't think anyone on here is
going to say oh well it was only a
certain group of people no it affected
the whole world
so sin is a global problem
it's a global problem
when we understand that I want you to
note Romans 5 15 which says but not as
the offense so also is the free gift for
if through the offense of one many be
dead
so who are the menis yeah I like that uh
naturally NYS the adamites it affected
the atomites meaning everybody the whole
the whole world
right so watch this for if through the
offense of one that's the first atom
many be dead
much more the grace of God and the gift
by Grace which is by one man Jesus
Christ who is the who is the who is he
everyone he's the
second Adam
has abound unto many now here's my
question for you
who is the many
in the first half of that verse for if
through the offense of one many be dead
who is the many there let me let me ask
this question
would the many in the first half of the
verse be the same many in the second
half of the verse
yes or no
would the many in the first half of the
verse
for if through the offense of one many
be dead meaning all
so the many in the first part is all
then the gift by Grace which is by one
man Jesus Christ has a bound unto the
same many
put a seven in the chat if that makes
sense to you
the same
many
that were sentenced to death
are the same many through whom the gift
is now presented to
let's keep reading and not as if and not
as it was by one that sinned so is the
gift for the judgment
was by one unto condemnation but the
free gift is of many offenses unto
justification let's keep reading
for If by one man's offense death
reigned by one much more they would
receive abundance of Grace and of the
gift of righteousness shall reign in
life by one Jesus Christ therefore as by
the offense of one judgment Came Upon
all men how many men everyone all men to
condemnation so let me ask you a
question how many is that all
how many is that all
would you say that all is some
or is that all
all
okay it's all it's everyone
so therefore as by the offensive one
judgment Came Upon all men to
condemnation even so by the
righteousness of one the free gift came
upon all men onto justification of life
meaning
all men may have an opportunity to
receive justification that's what the
text is telling us the same all in the
first half of the verse it is the same
all in the last half of the verse we
couldn't say well all men were condemned
to death but only some men were offered
the gift of eternal life that wouldn't
make any sense according to the text
are y'all with me so far let's keep
moving
let's keep moving so here's what I want
you to here's what I want you to
understand here
so how is out how is all man
how are all men under the condemnation
of Adam's sin why is death on all men
well the answer is found in this text in
the book of Hebrews chapter 7 verse 9
and 10. notice what it says here and as
and as I may say so as not that and as I
may so say Levi also who receives tithe
paid tithe and Abraham
for he was yet in the loins of his
father when Melchizedek met him all
right so what does that mean
what is that saying
that Levi before he was born paid tithe
in Abraham
the reason why death passed upon all men
is because all men were in the loins of
Adam put a one in the chat if you if you
caught what I just said all men were in
the loins of Adam and as a result of
that death passed upon all men
yes it was genetic
if we can say that it was it was passed
on because all mankind was bound up in
the lines
of Abraham
I'm sorry in the loins of Adam
watch this
in Genesis 35 verse 10.
and God said unto him thy name is Jacob
thy name shall not be called anymore
Jacob but Israel shall be thy name and
he called his name Israel and God said
unto him I am God Almighty be fruitful
and multiply a nation and a company of
Nations shall be of thee and King shall
come out of thy what
die what everyone
thy loins
so now watch this Beloved the promise to
Jacob was out of his loins would come a
great nation would come a great
multitude would come Offspring so listen
to me if come on y'all Follow Me Now
if Jacob is a point is a is a is a uh
type of Christ then we know that Christ
is supposed supposed to produce a great
multitude
when you're in the loins of someone when
when Levi was in the loins of of Abraham
what it's saying is that Levi was inside
Abraham he was in Abraham put one in the
chat if you call what I just said to be
in the loins of someone is to be in them
he was in Abraham when all when all
mankind received that death sentence is
because they were in Adam
they were in Adam
so now we can begin to understand enough
and listen to me that that that
if we are going to be
in the loins
if we're going to be in
I'm just too excited about how to put
this
in the Old Testament Israel was a man
who out of his loins came 12
and out of their loins came a great
multitude
in the New Testament Israel is the man
Jesus now please don't get me wrong
don't think I'm saying oh wherever you
read Israel in the New Testament it's
talking about Jesus that's not what I'm
saying what I'm saying is that the Old
Testament Israel is a type of Jesus
so just as the Old Testament Israel
started as a man
and out of his loins came forth 12 and
out of their loins came for the great
multitude so Jesus starts as a man but
he is going to produce 12. that means 12
are going to come out of his loins now
how does that happen does Jesus get
married
does Jesus get married and have a wife
and you know they they come together and
they bear children is that how he gets
the 12
how does he get to 12.
how do these get how does he get these
12 children
how does he get these 12 disciples
see I need y'all to see this go with me
to Hebrews chapter 2 verse 10.
for it became him for who all things are
and by whom all things are in bringing
many sons onto glory to make the captain
of their salvation perfect through
suffering for both he that Sanctified
and they who are Sanctified are all of
one for which cause he's not ashamed to
call them Brethren so notice how it says
in bringing many sons unto Glory
now let's keep moving
saying I will declare thy name unto my
brethren in the midst of the church will
I sing praise unto thee and again I will
put my trust in him now watch this next
verse y'all watch this next sentence and
again behold I so who is the I said who
is the I there
behold I
let's say to that I is short for
somebody who would that I be short of
whose name starts with an i
come on
behold I
I
Israel
they say Pastor no no no no no no that's
not talking about Israel watch this
behold I and the children which God has
given me the children so does Israel
have children does Jesus have children
yes
you want to know who the children of
Israel are
yeah
do y'all want to know who the children
of Israel the children of Israel are
those who are the children of Jesus
come on y'all put put put a five in the
chat if y'all to follow the children of
Israel
are the children of Jesus
let me demonstrate
guess what text is being quoted here in
Hebrews chapter 2 verse 13. y'all want
to know where this quote is taken from
behold I and the children which God has
given me I'm gonna do a little pop quiz
right here who can tell me where that
statement comes from behold I and the
children which God has given me who said
that anybody know who said that and what
was a context
anyone know I know there's a little
delay so I'm just gonna wait I'm just
gonna wait just for a moment all right
all right it's not popping up so let's
go
Genesis chapter 33 verse 4 and Esau ran
to meet him that is Jacob whose name is
now Israel
Esau ran to meet him and embraced him
and fell on his neck and kissed him and
they wept and he lifted up his eyes and
saw the women and the children
and said who are those with thee and he
said the children which God has
graciously given thy servant
hmm
Israel said that y'all
Israel said that
this is being directly attributed to
Jesus behold I
Israel
and the children that God has given me
so how does Jesus get children
he doesn't get them from marrying it's
not bloodline
Jesus never married anybody I need y'all
to understand
it's not bloodline that's not how he
gets children
the Bible tells us in second Corinthians
5 17 therefore If any man be in Christ
he is a new
preacher
all things are passed away behold all
things are become new so how does Jesus
get children because I need y'all to
understand this right
it is possible to be a child of Abraham
and yet not a child of Jesus
did y'all hear what I just said
it is possible to be a child of it
remember Jesus talking to he said I know
you're the Seed of Abraham but but your
father is the devil because you seek to
kill me
so yes you can actually be Of The
Bloodline of Abraham and yet not a child
of Christ
now
listen y'all
for that reason alone
we need to understand that is it is not
being a child of Abraham that saves you
it is being a child of Jesus
that's what saves you
therefore whether the children of
Abraham are black or white
or yellow
or brown or green
literally means nothing
when it comes
to the question of
who is going to be saved
so the fact that that many people are
getting caught up in the question of
what color were the descendants of
Abraham
foreign
if y'all want to argue about that feel
free
let me tell you it literally has nothing
to do with salvation why because only
the children of Christ are saved only
the children of Israel are saved do I
need to say that again think what I
think about what I just said only the
children of Israel will be saved
but see so many of us look to the flesh
we look to the Israel of the Old
Testament we say oh man I'm part of you
you might think I'm part of that
Offspring if you could even prove that
but you're like ah look so you think
that brings you in in in in favor with
God no beloved no no no no you can be of
the Seed of Abraham and be the devil I
know those who call themselves Jews and
are not
so you know what yeah there are Jews
beloved of different colors absolutely
absolutely
but it's not your color that saves you
it's not your color that commends you to
God
there are white devils and there are
black devils
and there are yellow devils and there
are brown devils
are y'all following me
we're just laying this out from the
Bible
we're just letting us out from the Bible
it is the children of Israel that will
be saved and when I say Israel I'm
talking about Jesus the children of
Jesus and how does Jesus get children
the Bible says watch this if you be
Christ then are you Abraham's seed and
heirs according to the promise so
if you are in the loins of Christ
if you are in Christ
did you catch that if you are in Christ
then God recognizes you as part of the
promise
the promise still is to Abraham
but God says the way that you get into
Abraham is by getting into my son
so if you're in Christ then you're
Abraham's seed
not if you're Abraham's seed then you're
in Christ big difference y'all
I'm Abraham see so I'm in Christ no no
no no I am Christ's so I am Abraham's
seed
are y'all following me
are y'all catching this
but there's more we're going over but
listen y'all there is more trust me I'm
getting there
I'm getting there let's keep moving
let's keep moving so if you're Christ
you're Abraham's seed your heirs
according to the promise notice again
with me Galatians 3 8 and the scripture
foreseen that God would justify the
Heathen through faith preach the gospel
unto Abraham saying in thee shall All
Nations be blessed so the question then
becomes the question then becomes who
are these heathens who are these heathen
that God promised
would be saved through Abraham
would be justified through Abraham now
um our brothers and sisters of a
different persuasion will say well these
Heathen are nothing more than other
Israelites right uh the the uh the
northern tribes right you remember
Israel was split into two there was the
southern Kingdom the northern kingdom
you got Israel yeah Judah so these are
just you know those other uh uh
Israelites but
we have to actually go back to the
context
of where this text came from where
they're quoting and I want you to note
in galatia in Genesis chapter 12 this is
where God first gets that promise and I
will make of thee a great nation and I
will bless thee and make thy name great
and thou shall be a blessing and I will
bless them that bless thee and curse him
that cursed thee and in these are all
the families of the earth be blessed so
our question is very simple
who were the families of the earth that
God was talking about when he said it
does that does that make sense
that's a fair question right who are the
families of the earth God is talking
about here in Genesis chapter 12. so do
y'all want to know do you want to know
who the families of the Earth are that
would be blessed in Abraham
because we gotta look at the context
so if we go back one chapter two
chapters
please know this
now these are the generations of the
sons of of Noah Shem ham and japheth and
unto them were Sons born After the flood
I'ma keep reading
so after he goes through the genealogy
of japheth he then says by these were
the odds of the Gentiles divided in
their lands everyone after his tongue
after their families in their Nation
would these families constitute the
families of the Earth
when God is giving this promise is
Israel as a nation even in existence
when God is giving this promise who are
the families of the earth outside the
loins of Abraham because not everybody's
in the Lawrence of Abraham
remember that everybody was in the loins
of Adam
everybody was even in the lines of Noah
but everybody was not in the lines of
Abraham
so so when God has given this promise
the context of the promise is the
Gentiles and he goes on to list Shem and
I mean ham and japheth and he's and he's
going through their genealogy verse 20.
These are the sons of ham after their
families after their tongues in their
countries and in their Nations
Genesis 10 31 these are the sons of Shem
after their families after their tongues
in their lands after the Nations and not
verse 32 these are the families of the
sons of Noah after their Generations in
their Nations and by these were the
Nations divided in the earth After the
flood I need y'all to understand that
the in context of the promise the
families are the sons of Noah
everybody
are y'all following this
they are the sons of Noah it's not just
one group of people it's everybody which
is which falls right in line with
everything we're seeing so far
sin Came Upon not a nation but the whole
world God came into the world to redeem
those under the sentence of death that's
everybody
this is why Revelation 7 9 says I after
this I beheld and lower great multitude
which no man could number of all Nations
and kindreds and people and tongues
stood Before the Throne and before the
lamb with clothed with white robes and
Palms in their hands I need you to
understand beloved that the people
standing Before the Throne are not from
a particular family
it's from everybody
so
the next question we need to ask is is a
it's a profound one
but the question is this
if we see that the promise of Salvation
is not granted to a particular group of
people alone
then what about
what about this idea that
the
the true Israelites can be identified
by the fact of the transatlantic slave
trade because the prop the the curses
that came from Deuteronomy 28
actually
reflect or actually point to
the transatlantic slave trade and this
is how we can know that the true
Hebrew Israelites
were African or black you know what we
would call African-American how how can
we I mean
how
how is one to answer that question
let's look at Deuteronomy 28.
let's look at Deuteronomy 28 are y'all
are y'all good with this
this is Bible study is that all right
we're teaching the word of God okay
so so let's take a look at this watch
Deuteronomy 28 verse whoa Deuteronomy 28
verse 15. my computer just now
Deuteronomy 28 verse 15. so I want you
to note the promise here right
it says
but it shall come to pass if thou will
not hearken unto the voice of the Lord
thy God to observe to do all his
Commandments and his statutes which I
command you to say that all these curses
shall come upon thee and overtake thee
and what are these curses thy Sons thy
daughters shall be given unto other
people and Thine Eyes shall look and
shall fail with longing for them all the
day long and there shall be no might in
thine hand so people say hey look this
is what happened during a slave trade
look this is the direct fulfillment of
what happened to black people in America
um how about Deuteronomy 28 33 and the
fruit of our land and all thy labors
shall a nation which thou knowest not
eat up America see that guys
this is America this is what America did
to black people and thou shall be not
only oppressed and crushed away so shall
thou be mad for the sight of Thine Eyes
which Thou shalt see and black people
had to endure all kinds of cruelties
they went a lot of them went mad how
about this verse 41 thou shall begets
sons and daughters but Thou shalt not
enjoy them for they shall go into
captivity see look another clear sign of
this being fulfilled in the
transatlantic slave trade and how about
this and the Lord shall scatter thee
among the people from the one end of the
Earth onto the other and there Thou
shalt serve other gods which thou which
thou nor that nor thy fathers have known
even wood and Stone
and the Lord shall bring thee into Egypt
again with ships
this is taken as evidence that the
transatlantic slave trade which utilized
ships to take slaves to America is a
direct fulfillment of Deuteronomy
chapter 28 the curse is there and what
the belief is that you know the fact
that black people are under a curse is
evidence that they are the true Israel
of God and I'm going to say this just
right up front y'all
to me this is a very convoluted to me
this is taking the slave master
mentality the same thing ham
was cursed and therefore that's how we
identify black people it's the same
thing except it's just glorified no no
no no we're still cursed but that proves
that we're Israel
so let's break this down
because I think it's the devil that
would like black people to believe that
they're cursed that's what I think what
do you think
what do y'all think
foreign
let me show y'all something
there is a parallel to this curse in
Leviticus 26 22 the curse that was
designated for Israel remember they are
coming out of the they're coming out of
Egypt and they're heading into the
promised land and God is telling them in
context context is everything y'all in
context God is telling them that if you
disobey me when you get into the land
that I'm going to give to you
these are all the things I'm going to do
to you these are all the things I'm
gonna I'm gonna allow to happen to you
we're talking about context here beloved
and the Very things I'm not going to say
let me just show you
in Leviticus 26 22 he says I will send
wild beasts among you which shall rob
you of your children and destroy your
cattle and make you few in number and
your highways shall be desolate so my
question is did Israel rebel against God
in the promised land did they yes or no
answer is yes so were these promises of
cursing
fulfilled when Israel rebelled against
God in the Promised Land
yes they were
listen to this
remember wild beasts
in Deuteronomy 28 verse 49 the Lord
shall bring a nation against thee from
far from the end of the Earth as Swift
as the eagle flyeth a nation whose
tongue thou shall not understand a
nation of fierce countenance which shall
not regard the person of the old or show
a favor to the young
is this America
is Deuteronomy 28 49 talking about
America the answer is no
it's not
it's not let me show you who it's
talking about
let me show you who it's talking about
go with me to Daniel chapter 7.
Daniel is envisioned here the Bible says
I saw four great beasts not pause for a
second what kind of beasts are these are
these tamed beasts or wild beasts what
do y'all think
what do y'all think tame these or wild
beasts that Daniel sees in vision
these are wild beasts let me go back let
me go back
and I will also send wow peace among you
which shall rob you of your children
okay let's go forward
Daniel 7.
four great beasts came up from the sea
diverse one from another the first was
like a lion and had what what did it
have y'all
it had eagles wings
now if you understand anything about
prophecy you will know that this first
Beast of four wild beasts represents
Babylon and what did Babylon do
Babylon
besieged Jerusalem and took their people
captive and slayed their young and their
old what I'm trying to demonstrate to
you right now beloved is this the
prophecy was fulfilled in the Babylonian
destruction of Jerusalem not America
in the Babylonian destruction of
Jerusalem and I'm gonna demonstrate that
for you because he's saying well you
could say well it was fulfilled then but
it was also also fulfilled later we're
going to come back to that
I need y'all to see this this is Babylon
destroying Jerusalem for the very reason
God said you're going to be destroyed
now check this out y'all because there
was a forgiveness clause in this curse
that many don't recognize let me let me
read it to you in Leviticus 26 40. if
they shall confess their iniquity and
the iniquity of their fathers and the
iniquity of their fathers
and the iniquity of their fathers with
their trespass which they trespass
against me and that also they have
walked contrary unto me and that I have
also walked contrary unto them and have
brought them into the land of their
enemies if then their uncircumcised
Hearts be humbled and they they then
accept of the punishment of their
iniquity
then will I remember my Covenant with
Jacob and also my Covenant with Isaac
and also my Covenant with Abraham well I
remember and I will remember the land
the land also shall be left of them and
shall endure her sabbaths and it goes on
do y'all realize
that
this was fulfilled
let's go to Daniel 9. let's go to Daniel
9. Daniel is in prayer that's right
y'all Africans were not enslaved because
they somehow rebelled against God
that's the that is the very reason slave
masters used how it it is mind-boggling
that we would actually take the argument
of slave masters and embrace it
yep we were cursed of God and that's why
we became slaves because we're the
Israelites really
really
that sounds rather demonic to me
and I've known people genuinely believe
it because it gives it gives us a sense
of ah I am somebody like I am important
but also I'm being cursed because but I
am important I do belong God does love
me beloved you don't need to prove
your bloodline
to come to the realization that God
loves you
and beloved listen to me while the white
slave owner was absolutely and
profoundly Wicked
it does not mean that there were not
other white people who were profoundly
righteous doing the right thing fighting
against that kind of iniquity meaning
that God has children of every color
race and nationality
come on come back to the screen Daniel 9
4. Daniel is in captivity and watch what
he prays and I prayed unto the Lord my
God and made my confession and said oh
Lord the great and Dreadful God keeping
the Covenant and mercy to them that love
him and to them that keep his
Commandments we have sinned whoa what
did God say if they remember their sins
if they confess us confess the sins of
their fathers watch this Daniel prays we
have sinned and committed iniquity and
have done wickedly and have rebelled
even by departing from thy precepts and
from thy judgments neither have we
hearken unto thy servants the prophets
which spake in thy name to our Kings our
princes our fathers and to all the
people of the Land O Lord righteousness
belongeth unto thee but unto us
confusion of faith of face as this as it
is this day to the men of Judah and to
the inhabitants of Jerusalem and unto
all Israel that are near and them that
are far off through all the countries
whether thou has driven them because of
their trespass against thee Daniel is
speaking as this is fulfilled in the in
the Captivity of the Babylonian
captivity
oh Lord to us belong confusion of Faith
to our Kings to our princes to our
fathers because we have sinned against
thee to the Lord Our God belongs mercies
and forgiveness though we have rebelled
against him neither have we obeyed the
voice of the Lord Our God to walk in his
laws and to keep and to set before which
he set before us by his servants the
prophets are y'all seeing this
this was fulfilled beloved not in
American slavery but in Babylonian
slavery and God gave that forgiveness
Clause if you repent I'm gonna bring you
back out of the land if this was talking
about Black Americans we would
what are we still doing here
why aren't we brought back to our land
come on follow me
follow this watch this y'all I need you
to see this we're building a case
throughout the entire scripture we're
not we're not just taking a little here
and then okay we'll no we're building an
entire case and I need you to see what
comes next so in Daniel 9
Daniel is praying because of the
rebellion of Israel the the the the
promise was given you're going to be
cursed but if you confess your sins I'm
gonna bring you back into the land and
while Daniel is praying
an angel descends
wait wait I gotta read this it says yay
all Israel have transgressed the law
even by departing that they might not
obey the voice watch this y'all
therefore the curse is poured Upon Us
hmm
and the oath that is written in the law
of Moses the servant of God because we
have sinned against him and he has
confirmed his word which he spake
against us and against our judges that
judge us by bringing upon us a great
evil for under the whole Heaven has not
been done as has been done upon
Jerusalem beloved
you cannot read even though there are
many similarities
don't get me wrong
you can't
you trade something that occurs way
later into the context of what the text
is actually talking about
the Forgiveness Clause sets us up for
Daniel 9. why is that so important
because I need y'all to see this I need
y'all to see this Daniel is given a
prophecy
in the very same chapter
the angel hears Daniel's prayer
confessing the sins of his people now
watch this
the angel comes to Daniel and note the
beginning words
70 weeks are determined upon thy people
and upon thy holy city now I'm not going
to read the rest of this because it's a
whole prophecy in fact let me just let
me just stop here verse 25. know
therefore and understand that from the
going forth of the Commandment to
restore and to build Jerusalem unto the
Messiah the prince shall be and then he
gives a time period so let's stop right
here
let's stop right here we gotta stop
right here
I'm just going to build in this for a
moment
Daniel has been given a prophecy the
prophecy states that in 70 weeks
something's going to happen in 70 weeks
in that time period the Messiah is going
to come now remember the Messiah is the
one that has the offer of salvation
and God is telling his people you need
to get ready because the very one who is
coming who is able to forgive you of
your sins
he will be here in this 70-week prophecy
foreign
is given and the Bible says
from this time period if you count 70
weeks it'll take you to the Messiah
within that time period
why is it significant y'all
the Reason God called Israel
the Reason God caught and Natasha I see
a question why so much hatred towards
the melody the melanated then
because the devil's the devil
because the devil's the devil that's why
and let me tell you not only is there so
much hatred towards those with melanin
In Their Skin there's the devil has a
lot of hatred
for those who don't have melanin in
their skin
what we need to understand beloved is
that the devil hates everybody
he's trying to destroy all of humanity
he hates the Chinese people
that's why he wants to keep the gospel
totally locked away from them the Bible
totally locked away from them
foreign
he doesn't have a favorite he hates all
mankind but let me tell you who he hates
most specifically he hates those who
reflect Christ that's who he really
hates
that's who he really hates see when we
get to the place we're like oh he hates
me because because he hates me in
particular because I'm black what that
does is it begins to to feed the spirit
of Pride that says I am better than
others because I'm black I am favorite
of God because I'm black
God likes me especially because of my
skin color
God likes me especially because of the
bloodline that I come from
and beloved
that picture of God is why there are
atheists today
are y'all following me
this is why Jesus says look whoever's in
me they're my children
those who deal with the will of my
father
those are my brothers and sisters those
are my children
I know I know I know you I know you're
the Seed of Abraham but your father is
the devil
are you feeling me
so God calls Israel for this purpose
watch this arise Shine for thy light has
come and the glory the Lord has risen
upon thee for Behold The Darkness shall
cover the Earth and grow darkness of
people but the Lord shall arise upon
thee Israel and His glory shall be seen
upon thee Israel and the Gentiles shall
come to thy light Israel and Kings to
the brightness of my Rising Israel but
Israel failed to live up to what God
called them to be which was a light to
the Gentiles a light to those in
darkness
God set aside Israel not because he
liked Israel better than everybody else
but because he loved everybody else
Israel I'm gonna use you to save as many
people as I possibly can
and what did Israel in the Old Testament
do they were like nah we Israel nope
nope don't minister to those Romans do
not Minnesota those Romans don't minute
they are our enemies we hate them
they persecute us
and when Jesus wouldn't get down with
their with their Spirit of hate you know
what they did they killed him
so let me throw something out here y'all
because you need to understand this what
look
I'm just giving a scenario okay
if Jesus came back
and he was black
how many how many of my white brothers
and sisters will be like praise him pray
wait what
how many of you might suddenly not want
to go to heaven
if Jesus came back in a color you didn't
expect
and for many of us
of us was back in a color you didn't
expect how many of you be like yeah well
I'm not going because he the devil
the way I know that it'll be a
counterfeit is if he's white
beloved I need you to understand that
the spirit of hate is a spirit of hate
it doesn't matter how we disguise it
doesn't matter how we hide it the spirit
of hate is the spirit of hate
we can argue about genealogies and about
skin color and about all the stuff but
beloved if you don't have the DNA of
Jesus
if you don't have the DNA of Jesus and I
need you to understand the DNA of Jesus
is not in bloodline the DNA of Jesus
means the divine nature attributes
that's the DNA of Jesus you might have
the DNA of Abraham all day long but if
you don't have the DNA of Jesus sorry
sorry
the only only those with the DNA of
Christ are going to be saved
catch what I just said only those with
the DNA of Christ will be saved and the
DNA of Christ cannot be attained
literally it cannot be attained by
bloodline it can only be attained by
being born again whose DNA do you have
if you are depending beloved
on Abraham's DNA
if you find your self-worth in the fact
that you are an offspring of Abraham
y'all are in trouble
because it's not his DNA that saves us
it is Jesus's DNA do you have the divine
nature attributes
which calls us to love even our enemies
which cause us to have the fruit of the
spirit love joy peace long suffering
gentleness goodness Faith meekness
Temperance you want to find an Israelite
find somebody that has those attributes
and you have found in Israelite
watch this what think think I'm making
this up watch this
the 70-week prophecy why does God give
70 weeks he could have said 75 weeks he
could have said 80 weeks it's up to God
to decide how long but he says 70 weeks
before the Messiah comes or is a time
period in which the Messiah will come
well what is the significance of 70
weeks let me tell you
70 weeks is 70 times 7.
y'all not feeling me man
70 we
've been
why is that number significant come with
me come with me to Matthew chapter 18.
then Peter came to him Jesus and said
Lord how often shall my brother sin
against me and I forgive him till seven
times Jesus said unto me I say not on TV
until certain times but until 70 times
7. 70 times 7 beloved is the number of
forgiveness complete forgiveness so what
God is telling Israel is you have 70
times seven I'm gonna extend Mercy to
you I'm gonna allow you to come back
into your Land Jerusalem I'm gonna bring
you out of Babylon you're going to come
back into your land
and you have 77s
before the Messiah comes the very one
who can pay your debt the very one who
can forgive your sins
if you reject him Israel
there's not another forgiveness clause
for you as a people
no something else is going to happen
if you reject him Israel I'm gonna show
you what's gonna happen so watch this
what notice what Jesus says so we see 70
times 7 is number forgiveness right
right after Jesus says 70 times 7 look
at what he says next watch this
put a one in the chat if you're
following are we good
this is Bible study we're studying the
word of God
your study was studying the word of God
all right
give me one second give me one second
okay
so check this out right after Jesus says
70 times 7 notice what he says next
therefore is the kingdom of heaven like
unto a certain King which would take
account of his servants and when he had
begun to reckon one was brought unto him
which owed him ten thousand talents so
remember this is right after Jesus
speaks of the 70 times seven
one was brought into him that owed him
ten thousand talents watch this but as
much for as much as he had not to pay
his Lord he commanded him to be Soul
then his wife and children and all that
he had and payment was to be made the
servant therefore fell down and
worshiped him saying Lord have patience
with me I will pay the all the Lord then
the Lord of that servant was moved with
compassion and loosed him and forgave
him the Dead
but the same servant went out and found
one of his fellow servants which owed
him a hundred Pence and laid hands on
him and took him by the throat saying
pay me what you owe me now let me break
this down for you okay
my here's my question
who is
who is the the master in this parable
would y'all say the master is God in
this Parable put a one in the chat if
the master is God in the parable
just follow me
yeah
is is who is the master in the story the
one who forgave that's God right that's
God
if I were to ask him hmm
how did the servant get in debt because
I want you to understand here the
servant is Israel
the servant is the nation of Israel
now how do they get into debt with God
oh we sinned against you
and as a result we ended up in
Babylonian captivity yeah follow me
as a result we ended up in Babylonian
captivity
and and and and and God being merciful
let forgave the debt
and brought you out of Babylon Israel
forgave you are y'all with me now watch
this watch this watch this watch this so
so
the servant is set free now watch this
then the Lord that servant was moved
with compassion and lose him and forgave
him the debt come on come back to
Jerusalem I forgive you for your your
crazy stunts and for your rejecting of
me I'm letting you out of Babylon come
now watch this but the same servant went
out and found one of his fellow servants
which owed him a hundred pens and laid
hands on him and took him by the throat
saying pay me that you owe me let me ask
you a question who do you think this
servant is
who do you think this servant is that
Israel finds
and lays hands on him
lays hands on him
who is that servant
may I suggest something to you
let's just look at that term laid hands
for a moment I want you to check this
out
the Bible says oh no man anything but to
love one another for he that loveth
another has fulfilled the law Troy
exactly
let me ask you something
does Jesus owe us
look at the text oh no man anything but
to love one another did Jesus come here
owing Humanity yes or no
absolutely we're told no watch this yo
we are told
to love one another because love is a
fulfilling of the law so you and I are
bound to owe one another love man I owe
you love I owe you love Jesus came to
this world to oh what he said look I'm
giving I'm here to give you love
I'm here to give you love
that's right your God is love and he
came here to give us love now watch this
the Bible says in Matthew 18 verse 29
and his fellow servant fell down in his
feet and besought him saying have
patience with me I will pay thee all
and he would not but when he cast him
into prison till he should pay the debt
I got a question for you did Jesus pay a
debt for us
did Jesus pay a debt for us
come on y'all
but what did we do
the Bible says all we like sheep have
gone astray we have turned everyone to
his own way and the lord has laid on him
the iniquity of us all Jesus took our
debt that we owed and paid it on our
behalf
and said I'm coming here
because I love you
hey I'm gonna pay your debt but what did
Israel do they grabbed them they laid
hands on him
see at a time they couldn't John 7 33
they sought him to take him but no man
laid hands on him because his hours was
not yet watch this John 7 44 and some of
them would have taken him but no man
laid hands on him John 8 20. these words
fake Jesus in the treasury as he taught
in the temple and no man laid hands on
him for his hours was not yet come now
watch this and as soon as he was come he
goes straight way to him that is Judas
and saith master and kissed him watch
this and his fellow servant let me come
back
oh man where are you I thought I had it
in the
let me come let me come
yeah
the text said they laid hands on him and
took him
they lit right after Mark 14 45 after
Judas kisses him they laid hands on him
and took him
and what did they do
they cast them in prison
yeah yeah yeah I see I know y'all were
like huh pass away they they cast them
in prison
until he should pay
the debt
so when his fellow servants saw what was
done they were very sorry and came and
told unto the Lord all that was done
then this Lord then his Lord after that
he had called him said unto him oh thou
Wicked servant I forgave thee all that
debt because you desired it of me
should not you have also had compassion
on my fellow servant even as I had pity
on thee and his Lord was Wrath and
delivered him to the tormentors so he
should pay all that was due unto him you
do understand that as a result of
rejecting Jesus
as a result of rejecting Jesus at the
end of that 70-week prophecy Jesus who
said hey man listen I'm gonna pay the
debt for you I love you no no we're
gonna
and they saw no mercy
foreign
as a result of their rejecting Christ
as a result of their rejecting the very
one that was to forgive them of their
sin
something happens to Israel y'all know
what happened right
let me break this out for you quickly
and then I got a few more points I need
to share and then we're going to wrap
this up don't tune out just follow me
follow me
and listen I see some of you saying
pastor I disagree with you the true
Hebrews are black I'm not arguing that
y'all can't disagree with me on that
because I'm not arguing that they are or
that they aren't
that's not my argument if that's your
argument listen man uh I will listen
I'll be like hey interesting
what I'm trying to say is
your bloodline has literally it's good
history
it's good information but it's not
information that's gonna save you
it's not information that's gonna save
you
if you don't have Jesus's blood
and how are you going to get that
because he didn't have any literal kids
how are you going to get Jesus's blood
he had no Offspring and yet he has
millions of Offspring why because the
way Jesus produces children is different
from the way that Abraham and and and
and and uh uh Jacob and everybody else
does
you must be born again
you must be born of the water and the
spirit that's how you become a child of
Israel that's how you become a child of
Jesus you got to be born of the spirit
so watch this
Jesus says to this rebellious people he
says listen
Matthew 21 verse 43 therefore I say unto
you the kingdom of God shall be taken
from you and given to a nation bringing
forth the fruits thereof beloved this is
right in the Bible it's right there the
kingdom of God shall be taken from you
Israel after the Flesh and given to a
nation bringing forth the fruits thereof
Jesus said this
he said I'm going to give you one sign
as a sign of Jonah
and y'all remember the story of Jonah
right three days and three nights he was
in the belly of the earth that pointed
forward to Jesus's three days and three
nights in the grave
but here's a powerful thing y'all that's
the part of Jonah's sign that we focus
on three nights in three days
listen to this
after no Jonah's three nights in three
days remember he spent 40 days preaching
that Nineveh was going to fall
but Yama what happened Nineveh repented
and as a result the city didn't fall
well I need you to understand this
beloved because Jesus is saying I am
that second Jonah not only is he the
second Abraham the second Isaac the
second Jacob not only is he the second
Adam but he's also the second Jonah
Jesus was in the belly of the Earth for
three days and three nights now watch
this that was 31 A.D roughly Jesus
ascends out of the belly of the way of
the whale out of the belly of the fish
out of the belly of the earth and he
goes to heaven but watch this
40 years later how many did I say
remember in the story of Nineveh it was
supposed to be 40 days before Nineveh
was destroyed but Nineveh repented and
they were not destroyed check this out
y'all 40 years after Jesus's death
burial and Resurrection guess what
happens to Jerusalem
because of their rejection of the
Messiah
the city
is destroyed
and if you read Joseph's account of that
destruction
many of the Jews were put on ships and
sent to Egypt
literally
you see
the reason that this that this is
significant y'all and we're coming we're
we're getting ready to close we're
coming to an end here
we got one more thing to talk about all
right so please follow me the reason
this is significant y'all
is because after this after Israel is
dispersed
God has given
truth to a new nation bringing forth the
fruits thereof
but he still calls them the children of
Israel why
because they are in Christ
Sona
um
whether you're of the literal seat of
Abraham
or not of the literal Seed of Abraham at
all
if you are a child of Christ
you are the Seed of Abraham
there is an Israel after the flesh
and we can argue all day long about who
that is
that's good historical information
I'm telling you
that's good history
it's like you know arguing about the
history of I'm from Jamaica so arguing
about the history of Jamaica you know
that's good history it's not salvational
but hey if that's what really meant yeah
that's cool then then hey talk about it
go ahead
but if you're talking about salvation
now you gotta separate the history of
Jamaica from what is actually
salvational
are you understand what I'm saying
your skin color and whose blood you have
in your veins literally literally has
nothing to do with salvation it is only
about the blood of the Lamb
do you have a blood of Jesus that's what
matters the Bible tells us the Bible
tells us in John 1 1 he came into a Zone
and his own received them not but as
many as received him to them gave ye
power to become the sons of God even to
them that believe on his name which were
born not of blood not of blood
not of blood everybody say that with me
ready one two three not of blood
that means it doesn't matter if you were
born of Abraham or not not of blood
if you have a Bible underline that in
your Bible highlight it in your Bible
not of blood
nor of the will of the flesh you the
your dad and your mom got together they
had no we're not talking about that
birth we're talking about being born of
God and even Nicodemus was like how does
that happen
Jesus are you sure
can a man go back into his womb and be
born again in mother's womb and be born
again
no
except to be born of the water
and of the spirit
you guys you need to understand this
because many of our many many young
listen
many people being led astray by this
many people being led astray by this not
only on that end but on the other end
because this same belief is present in
in white Evangelical churches that you
know God favors this group of people
all their prophecies are Israel centered
and they miss the entire point of the
Bible they miss the entire point of
Prophecy because they believe prophecy
is being fulfilled in the things that
are happening over in literal Jerusalem
and the devil doesn't care how he
deceives you
as long as he deceives you
Christ has redeemed us from the curse of
the law the Bible said being made a
curse for us for it is written curses
everyone that hangs on the tree that The
Blessing of Abraham might come on the
Gentiles through Jesus Christ that we
might receive the promise of the spirit
through faith but love and listen to me
listen carefully
God's people are not cursed the wicked
are cursed
Jesus Took the curse upon himself at the
cross in that 70-week prophecy Jesus
Took the curse upon himself so to say
that God's people today are identified
by cursing is diametrically opposed to
the scripture
God's people are not identified by the
curses they're identified by the
blessings
and if you are under the curse of if
someone is Under The Curse Of God
whatever that might be it's evidence
that God is not with them and they are
not with God
do not use the curses of the Bible to I
to
that is backwards y'all
why do I know that I'm loves of God
because I'm cursed no
no
it's the wicked that occurs the
righteous are blessed are you blessed
are those Remember The Sermon on the
Mount blessed blessed blessed blessed
the Bible says yea all that live will go
live will live Godly in Christ Jesus
shall suffer persecution persecution is
not curses y'all and curses are not
persecution they are two different
things they're two different things
all right
can y'all get me
can y'all give me 10 more minutes put a
one in the chat if you give me 10 more
minutes I totally were going to be
studying the word of God today that this
is a deep subject subject that requires
deep thinking so 10 more minutes
are y'all good with that
yes Deanda absolutely
we're not cursed we we are persecuted
but it doesn't mean that we're cursed
amen
amen all right
are y'all good
Revelation 12. come on y'all we're
almost there we're almost there
Revelation 12. they repaired a great
Wonder in heaven a woman clothed with
the sun and the moon under her feet and
upon our head a crown of 12 stars and
she being with child cry travailing in
birth and pain to be delivered I want
you to understand this woman
this woman represents the church
it represents Israel let me say it that
way the woman is symbolic of Israel
just as in the Old Testament uh
just as in the Old Testament the the
Natasha I see your question again and
you know what the only answer to that is
that
is sin
it's sin that's really all that it is
it's sin
I can hear the frustration in your
question and I get it all I can say is
it's sin
but remember this the devil hates
the devil hates all people and if he can
turn us against one another he believes
that his goal is accomplished
right
so look
this woman
that gives birth to Christ is not
symbolic of Mary it's symbolic of the
Old Testament Church
and the Bible tells us that
in verse 5
she brought forth a Mansa who was to
rule all nations with a rod of iron and
her child was caught up onto God into
his throne
so this is the catching up of Jesus and
then notice how Israel is described
after notice how the church is described
after and the woman that is Israel God's
people
fled Into the Wilderness where she has a
place prepared of God that they should
feed her there a thousand two hundred
and three score days what I want you to
understand beloved is super important at
this point
this
1260 year prophecy is crucial to
identifying Israel
see God doesn't have a 400 year prophecy
about Israel in the future he does have
a 1260 year prophecy identifying Israel
in the future and all I simply want to
say is this
if you cannot identify what this 1260
year period is and how
Israel fulfills this prophecy you have a
wrong understanding of who Israel is
do you understand what I just said
if you cannot identify
if you cannot identify this
1260 prophetic day period and tie it
into who you believe Israel is and this
is sometime after the Cross of Christ
you have the wrong picture of Israel
that's it
this is clear stuff here you can't make
these numbers up I'm not going into it
to today I'm simply saying if you want
to say I know who Israel is you must
identify what this Wilderness is what
this 1260 day or prophetic day period is
and how Israel fulfilled it from
beginning to end
there is not a 400 year prophecy
regarding Israel in the future there is
a 1260 year prophecy regarding Israel in
the future there is a 400 year prophecy
regarding Israel in the past that was
fulfilled that happened in the book of
Exodus there is not a 400 year prophecy
pointing to Israel in the future put a
one in the chat if you understand that
the Bible ultimately describes this
Israel in this way the dragon was rough
with the woman and went to make war with
the remnant of receipt which keep the
Commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus Christ the DNA
of the end time people of God is that
they keep the Commandments of God
and they have the testimony of Jesus
Christ
and if you're saying it's all 623 I
invite you to go back to my previous
sermon on the law of God
where I show the distinction
between the laws that required a temple
and a plot of land
versus the laws that did not require a
temple
or a plot of land
a nation a city
come on we are I promise you
I'ma just stop saying that the Bible
says whereby are given unto us exceeding
great and precious promises that by
these you might be partakers of the
divine nature the DNA Jesus's divine
nature attributes having escaped the
corruption that is in the world through
us this is the divine nature that God is
talking about not the Blood of Abraham
but the blood of Jesus
Jesus answered and said it verily verily
I say to the accepted man be born again
he cannot see the kingdom of God
Nicodemus said unto him how can a man be
born when he's old how can he enter the
second time into his mother's womb
and Jesus goes on to say that which is
Born the flesh is flesh that which is
born of the spirit is Spirit you must be
born again
this is why Romans 2 28 says for he is
not a Jew which is one outwardly neither
is that circumcision which is outward in
the flesh but he is a Jew which is one
inwardly and circumcision is that of the
heart in the spirit and not in the
letter whose praise is not of men but of
God
see I need you to understand that in the
Old Testament
people could become Jews
simply by being circumcised
and keeping those feast days
Esther 18 8 17.
and in the province and in every city
where the sort of the king's commandment
and his decree came the Jews had joy and
gladness and feast a feast and a good
day and many of the people of the land
became Jews
for the fear of the Jews fell upon them
in the Old Testament you could become a
Jew
but you have to be circumcised
in the New Testament you can still
become a Jew
but now Christ is our circumcision
If any man be in Christ he is a new
creature this is why acts 17 26 says
that he is made of one blood all nations
of men for the dwell on the face of the
Earth One blood
all nations of men
all right
this is my last point
and I cannot close without talking about
these two sticks
the word of the Lord came unto me again
same or over thou son of man
take the one stick and write upon it for
Judah
for the house of the children of Israel
and his companions
then take another stick and write upon
it for Joseph The Stick of Ephraim and
for all the house of Israel and his
companions
and join them one to another into one
stick and they shall become one in thine
hand
and when the children of Israel When the
Children of thy people shall speak unto
thee saying will thou not show us what
that means by these
say unto them thus say the Lord God
behold I will take the Stick of Joseph
which is in the hand of Ephraim and the
tribes of Israel his fellows and will
put them with him even with the Stick of
Judah and make them one stick and they
shall be one in my hand
and the sticks where on thou writers
shall be in thine hand before thine eyes
and say unto them
thus say the Lord God behold I will take
the children of Israel from among the
heathen
which they be gone and will gather them
on every side and bring them into their
own land and I will make them one nation
in the land upon the mountains of Israel
and one King shall be king to them all
and they shall no more be two Nations
neither shall they be divided into two
kingdoms anymore at all
the reason I want you to understand this
as weak as we close
in pastoral language as we close
is that there was a split between Judah
and Israel the northern kingdom and the
southern Kingdom
for several reasons
we're not going to get into those
reasons now but I just want you to
notice that
um Judah was overthrown by Babylon and
uh Israel the ten tribes Northern tribes
were overthrown by Assyria
and so this is why God's talking about
I'm going to bring these two sticks back
together but I want you to check this
out y'all notice what happens when us
when when uh Israel falls in the ninth
year of Jose of Jose the king of Assyria
took Samaria Samaria Samaria
Samaria
and carried Israel away into Syria and
placed them in Hala in the in and in
Heber by the river goes in and in the
cities of the medes
and the king of Assyria watch this you
guys the king of Assyria brought men
from Babylon and from Kutta and from
ABBA and from Hamad and from sephardium
and place them in the cities of Samaria
instead of the children of Israel and
they possessed Samaria and dwelt in the
cities thereof so what I want you to see
y'all what I want you to see is this
Israel literally becomes interbred with
Heathen Nations
they're no longer a pure lying
they're intermingling the bloodline is
being mixed with all these different
nationalities
man God is something else
God is something else
now Israel is mingled with other
nationalities
do y'all understand the significance of
that
when God brings these two sticks
together again what he is saying is I am
going to in one
in one stick have a great multitude of
every nation Kindred tongue and people
that no man could number and they will
all be the children
of Israel
of Jesus
the children of God
here's my closing text
wherefore remember that ye being in time
past Gentiles in the flesh
who are called uncircumcision by that
which is called the circumcision in the
flesh made by hands and some people say
no the Gentiles In the Flesh here were
the Samaritans these are these are the
Israelites who are Heathen well guess
what those Israelites who are Heathen
guess what they're mingled with
in this mingling of bloodline beloved
God is bringing into God is fulfilling
the promise that in Abraham would all
the nations of the earth be blessed
and so through Israel's failures and
their their their turning away from God
even in that
God was working through their captivity
and through their their scattering to
the winds God is working through those
events because Israel being rebellious
and and turning against God all these
different things happen with Israel and
yet God is working through them despite
this to bring about the Fulfillment of
his promise to Abraham
that you were at times without Christ
being aliens from the Commonwealth of
Israel and strangers from the Covenant
of Promise having no hope and without
God in this world but now in Christ
Jesus
you who are sometimes afar off are made
nigh by the blood of Christ
for he is our peace who has made both
one and has broken down the middle wall
of partition between us having abolished
in his flesh the enmity even the law of
Commandments contained in ordinances
to make of himself of Twain one new man
so making peace and that he might
reconcile both unto God in one body one
stick by the cross one stake
having slain the enmity thereof beloved
I appeal to you
today
that you be concerned with one thing
only
do I have the DNA of Jesus
the devil got caught up in his own
Beauty in heaven
and that's the same thing he's trying to
do now I'm white I'm superior
I'm black I'm superior
forget about what's on the inside the
devil says
look at you just look at you because
that's what he was doing looking at
himself
you see how the devil tries to feed
Pride
yeah man
you're special because
you are black you're special because you
are white
you're special because you are of this
particular bloodline and all of it
beloved tends to the spirit of
self-supremacy which is what got Satan
kicked out of heaven
don't fall for Satan's for Satan's stuff
y'all
I'm preaching this message not to blast
anybody not to you know make anybody
look stupid that I know some people get
on and they're like you know Adventists
and they they're trying to make people
look that's not what I'm trying to do
here I need y'all to understand that
right I'm not trying to Samantha that's
good I'm not trying to blast people I'm
not trying to be like that you know they
crazy they hypocrite I'm not I'm not
doing that all I'm saying
because I know they are genuine people
genuine people who are searching for
truth and they believe with everything
they have listen man some of these
people will run circles
and that's the problem
that's the problem let me close with
this
we Christians aren't used to doing
what we just did today
we're not used to actually sitting down
and having a Bible study that could
actually go to the I don't know how long
I talked
uh trust me my wife is going to tell me
how long I talked so y'all know y'all
pray for me but
we don't do this
but other people of other faiths are
doing this
believe that they are that they are
inaccurately coming to the scriptures
they're impressing people with their
knowledge of the word of God
convoluted as it may be they're willing
to get down and spend hours and hours
and hours and beloved many of our young
people are joining these movements
because they are impressed with man how
you know that how you know because we
don't do that how can we be sitting on
the truth of God's word
how can we be sitting on the truth of
God's word and not study it with as much
passion as some of our brothers and
sisters in some of these other movements
that doesn't make any sense to me
that makes no sense to me whatsoever
beloved
make sure
that you have the DNA of Christ
you want the DNA of Christ put that one
in the chat Lord
you realize today
it's not about
what my my literal bloodline it's about
the DNA of Christ put that in the chat
and I'm going to pray for you guys okay
let's put that one in the chat Lord I
want your DNA one in the chat Lord I
want your DNA
and let's pray heavenly father thank you
for speaking to us thank you Lord for
your word thank you for your truth
thank you Lord
that you sent your son into this world
to pay a debt for us
thank you Lord
that he was willing to pay the whole
debt
to pay it all
and yet Humanity was unkind to him was
unmerciful to him
Lord
teach us to have your DNA that we may
become the children of Israel
thank you Lord
thank you for all who will hear this
message and hear the voice of the spirit
thank you for all who have heard this
message today and heard the voice of the
spirit and Lord even for those
who have heard and are struggling with
this message because they believe what
they believe so intently I pray for them
that now might not be their time
but that their time will come
where they will see and understand this
thank you Lord
for giving us an opportunity to hear and
receive and understand truth may we take
advantage of this truth and live it out
in our lives as our prayer in Jesus name
amen and amen I want to invite everyone
um thank you all for praying for me uh
as I gave this message thank you for
praying for my voice as I was speaking
but I want to invite everyone to join us
on altar live
the link is going up in the chat
um we'll discuss the uh Sabbath school
as well as the sermon uh today Lord
today and how the Lord
um spoke what in what uh what moved you
what touched you and um
you guys be blessed
have a blessed Sabbath rest your Sabbath
and uh I will see you guys not next week
but the week uh the week after all right
so uh I think the link is up in the chat
and listen if y'all have any questions
on this presentation especially you know
if you're watching for the first time
please feel free to email me feel free
to uh uh to contact us you can go um you
can email uh Patrice at Living Mana uh
dot live and she will get those emails
to me if you want to connect with me if
you want to talk with me let me know
okay we will connect all right
so God bless you and
um have a good rest of your day
amen
thank you for worshiping with us today
if this is your first time visiting with
us we invite you to check out our
website at livingmanna.live there you
will learn more about our mission to
reach the world with the Gospel of Jesus
we have exciting live programs
throughout the week covering topics like
physical health mental health prayer
learning how to prove God's existence
and much more if you would like to
support the ministry you can click on
the tithe and offering link on our
website we ask that you continue to pray
for the church as God continues to open
doors for our programming to reach the
world thank you again for your prayers
and your support
foreign